<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Paul K. Jackow</title>
        <description>Paul Jackow&#39;s Blog</description>
        <link>http://logicliving.github.io//blog/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://logicliving.github.io//blog/feed.xml" rel="self"
        type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 23:23:39 -1000</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 23:23:39 -1000</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.0.3</generator>
        
        <item>
            <title>Third week Coding.</title>
            <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-is-the-time-going&quot;&gt;Where is the time going?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been a lot of copying and following along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-will-i-go-solo&quot;&gt;When will I go solo.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I so want to be able to anticipate what to do next, and be able to build an app from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess it comes with practice. I just want to be able to know the basics, so that I can run solo, and look up issues that arise on the fly. It seems like my hand is still being held. It is very frustrating, because my mentallity does not allow me to just move on. I need to dig in and recreate what we just did, in another format, in order to learn the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put together this blog using Jekyll. It took me some time to understand the workings of how the pages interact with each other, and then how to deploy to Git hub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 02:12:12 -1000</pubDate>
            <link>http://logicliving.github.io//blog#/2016/02/10/thirdweek.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://logicliving.github.io//blog#/2016/02/10/thirdweek.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Second week Coding.</title>
            <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;model-view-controller-relationship&quot;&gt;Model, View, Controller Relationship?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am trying to understand the relationship between the diffrent components of rails. How the diffrent components interact with each other is important to me. I found that the routes.rb is very important in specifying the paths as well as what will be created. Next the controller basically sends us to the view as well as to the database through the Model. The Model is basically letting us comunicate to the database using SQL. Once the data is obtained through the Model we are able to place it in a variable e.i @places and call on this variable in the view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;database&quot;&gt;Database.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I dont really know how to access the database, I assume it is done through ruby terminal. I will have to dove deeper into this in the upcoming week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to create a sample app from scratch, and hit a wall on how the naming conventions need to look in order for the MVC to work together. I finally got it through trial and error! Very time consuming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 02:12:12 -1000</pubDate>
            <link>http://logicliving.github.io//blog#/2016/02/10/secondweek.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://logicliving.github.io//blog#/2016/02/10/secondweek.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>First week Coding.</title>
            <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting-up-the-environment&quot;&gt;Setting up the environment.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took some time to get used to the vagrant environment. I now understand that in order to have a controlled environment with no problems this was the way to go. It is essentially a Virtual machine that has been setup in a controlled manner, with ruby on rails packeged inside with all the dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working-on-my-first-app&quot;&gt;Working on my first app.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently working on my first app called “Splurty”. It has been prestty easy to follow along, I focused on learning the terminal and as many commands as possible, as they pertain to the project, its creation, manipulation etc. Also focused on learning the Github commit process, as well as Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding that there are 2 databases, one that lives locally on your development environment and the other that lives on Heroku, is crucial, and can save a lot of time moving forward.
I learned that Heroku uses the Postgres SQL database natively and it is easier to run your app using this database for migration purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I am following along, in the back of my head I am thinking; How will I ever get a hang of this? The natural tendency is to try to back pedal, and have the concepts sink in my trying to recreate the steps just presented.  Instead I push on, trusting the process. I know I canot create the app on my own at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 02:12:12 -1000</pubDate>
            <link>http://logicliving.github.io//blog#/2016/02/01/firstweek.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://logicliving.github.io//blog#/2016/02/01/firstweek.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
